Have you discovered
Little accidents in life
It really comes as soon as it is said.
Like being
Mosquito bites
scald
Or when mom is cutting vegetables
accidentally cut my hand.
How to handle recovery fastest?
Traditional Chinese medicine treats illnesses based on
Wài yīn nèi yīn bù nèi wài yīn (Transliteration)
What about these external injuries I just mentioned?
It belongs to the bù nèi wài yīn (Transliteration)
I'll teach you
Several practical first aid tips
Simple and effective
Hu Naiwen starts his lecture
I am your old friend, Doctor Hu
I want to share this episode with you
1.2 ways to quickly relieve the itching caused by mosquito bites
2.How to stop bleeding from a cut on the hand? Four first aid steps.
3.Toothpaste or flour are not recommended; applying this one thing on burns prevents scarring.
4.Got splashed by oil while pan-frying fish or deep-frying food? 3 types of oil fight inflammation.
5.What to do if bitten by a dog? Apply one thing to heal faster.
2 ways to quickly relieve the itching caused by mosquito bites
Do you believe it?
A swollen area from a mosquito bite.
It almost
turned into cellulitis
On a network platform
A mother shared
What is this online platform?
The editor told me.
It is a social platform
that young people love to use.
This mother
She said she went to the coffee shop
Bitten six bumps.
One of the bumps.
Getting itchy
There is also tissue fluid seeping out
Pain to the point of being unable to walk
finally went to the dermatologist and
found out that had an infection.
Doctors say
If it gets worse
that is
Cellulitis
Wow, that's too serious.
My grandma always told me to put some saliva on it
The itching will go away soon.
Is this useful?
The editor
I'll tell you a story
There is a man playing mahjong
Fighting all night
Feeling a little itchy at any time
thought it was a mosquito bite
Just applied it like this with saliva.
The result
After playing mahjong all night
Get up
Well, what happened?
A snake died behind
What Why
So the snake licked the saliva on this person's back.
Poisoned to death
Although it's just a story
But saliva is a little toxic.
When I was in college
Read
Human saliva and dog saliva
All are poisonous
Can temporarily relieve itching
So someone
think it will be less itchy after applying it
But I don't recommend
You use saliva to relieve the itch
Why
There are many unknown things
about saliva
Things like bacteria.
Especially children
Scratch it when it itches
Wipe saliva with dirty hands
What's that thing
on that hand?
Prone to bacterial infection
Or some other source of disease
I'll tell you
Natural remedies for itching without medication
Learn these two methods.
Tip 1: Ice for five minutes
Make the blood vessels constrict.
Reduce itching and swelling
If you don't have ice cubes
Can it be replaced with something else?
Do you have an iced drink?
Take the drinks from the refrigerator
Then wrap it with a clean cloth
Just put it in that place.
Then what
Press it for ten seconds.
Press for ten seconds
This lasts about five minutes.
can
Relieve the itchy feeling
Tip 2: Use a used tea bag
Tea bags contain tannic acid
It's called tannic acid, right?
Has a convergent effect
Can constrict blood vessels
Reduces oozing and itching sensations
There are many black mosquitoes in summer
Are there any natural ways to repel mosquitoes?
have
Use Cloves
Clove is a traditional Chinese medicine
Its aroma
It can also repel mosquitoes
You can buy it at a Chinese medicine store.
The so-called clove.
Something that's also not expensive.
Divide it into small bags
Place it on the balcony window
Every corner
Non-toxic and safe, quite good
How to stop bleeding from a cut on the hand? Four first aid steps.
Not just mosquito bites
Another common occurrence
It's in the kitchen
Cutting something and getting your hand
Of course
Mothers can cook their own food
That's the best
Then you must understand
People in the kitchen
Who hasn’t been cut by a knife?
When you are chopping vegetables
When peeling fruit
Accidentally
If you don't pay attention
Wow, I got it.
How should you deal with it?
Many mothers use patches to apply
Yes or no
Just one
Just a bandage
That's right
What to do if you cut your hand and the bleeding won't stop
Remember these four steps
The first step is to stop the bleeding
The method of stopping bleeding is simple
Clean gauze or napkins
Put pressure on the wound to stop the bleeding
Step 2: Disinfect the wound
Wait until the bleeding has stopped
Start using it to clean wounds
Use alcohol, iodine tincture, povidone-iodine, etc. to disinfect.
Step 3: Apply medicine
Confirm that there is no further bleeding
Apply
an antibacterial ointment
Prevent infection
The fourth step: bandaging
Use what just said
adhesive plaster
Or gauze
Just wrap it up
There is a master of hemostasis in traditional Chinese medicine
Do you know what it's called?
called Panax notoginseng
It doesn't just stop bleeding.
The best place
It is able to
Preventing scabs
No scars left on wounds
Let me tell you an interesting story
More than forty years ago
I take my kid to play ball.
As a result, I fell down
Then we have to
Let the surgeon take a look.
The surgeon
drawer is opened
I saw him there
Put a bottle of medicine
That is to say
Even Western medicine uses Yunnan Baiyao
The main ingredient of Yunnan Baiyao
is Panax notoginseng
He can help stop the bleeding.
Make wounds heal faster
Even surgeons use Chinese medicine
That means the effect of Yunnan Baiyao
It's really good.
That's what mean.
Toothpaste or flour are not recommended; applying this one thing on burns prevents scarring.
Doctor
Last time I poured hot water to drink
Then on the way back to the room
Hot water drips
onto my toes
My feet hurt
Go take a cold shower immediately
While rushing, I thought about what you said
Sprinkle salt
After sprinkling salt, wow
There really are no blisters.
Hey
This one
You reacted pretty quickly.
Otherwise toes
It may become
Caramel crispy, right?
Yeah, don't do that.
Sprinkling salt is a good idea
If you don't want to leave scars
If you want your skin
to be hydrated
I have another great method
It's just talcum powder and olive oil
Mix these two things together
Apply on burned areas
Talcum powder with olive oil works well
I remember when
About forty years ago.
When I first became a Chinese medicine practitioner
One of my classmates
He got burned accidentally
The wound has not healed
after a week or two.
I suggested that he mix talcum powder with olive oil
to make a paste
Then apply it to that place
It will be fine soon
Wow, it's been a week or two.
No scars left
Really great
You will definitely ask
Where can I buy talcum powder?
You can buy it at a Chinese medicine store.
Cheap and easy to use
What if I can't buy it?
You can also use rhubarb powder
It has the effect of cooling blood and reducing inflammation
It's a good alternative
And talcum powder
Besides the Chinese medicine pharmacy
You may also buy it in bookstores
In bookstores, it is called abacus powder
Because in the past, when people used to use the abacus
Use some talcum powder
That abacus will be more slippery
Some people use toothpaste or flour
Is it okay to apply it on the wound?
Toothpaste or flour
It has no bactericidal effect
No anti-inflammatory effect
So I don’t recommend it.
Got splashed by oil while pan-frying fish or deep-frying food? 3 types of oil fight inflammation.
In addition to burns
Mothers
When you are frying fish or frying food in the kitchen
Would it also get splashed by oil?
Oh, when splashed by oil.
It really hurts.
At this time
If you have three kinds of oil
Apply it quickly and it will be fine soon
Three kinds of oil
1. flaxseed oil
2. olive oil
3. Sesame oil
Any cold pressed oil will do
Pay attention
Extracted oil
Probably not.
Why is cold pressed oil effective?
flaxseed oil
olive oil
Sesame oil
They are cold pressed
Unrefined version
When you get burned
These oils
Rich in natural antioxidants
and essential fatty acids
Flaxseed oil
contains Omega-3 fatty acids
Olive oil and its phenolic compounds
Sesamol in sesame oil
Both have anti-inflammatory properties
Antioxidant Effect
After applying
Can help
Relieve burns
Redness, swelling, and inflammation
And
Moisturizes the skin and accelerates repair
Can prevent wounds
from drying out and peeling
What to do if bitten by a dog? Apply one thing to heal faster.
My friend was bitten by a dog last week
Bleeding on the spot
I was so scared after hearing this
take it easy
Dog bites
Not that you want
It happens. It happens.
But seriously
There really was a time when got bitten.
Western medicine first thing
ask you to go to the hospital.
Give you a Tetanus Toxoid
Or a rabies vaccine
etc.
Of course before that
He will help you wash the wound first
Disinfection and then
Let's continue with this medical treatment.
But if you do this
The wound hasn't healed yet.
I've encountered such a case.
Probably about a year ago.
There is a patient.
His wound hasn't healed for a long time.
have tried Chinese and Western medicine, but nothing can help.
Finally found me
I helped him with treatment.
About a month
The wound finally healed
So amazing
What magic elixir did you use?
I tell you
Longleaf Garden Burnet Root
This is the wisdom of the ancients
For example, inZhǒu hòu bèi jí fāng (Transliteration)
Gé hóng(Transliteration)said
He said to grind the Longleaf Garden Burnet Root into powder
Like taking Chinese medicine
Take once or twice a day
Then put this powder
Apply it on the wound
It can heal the wound
Okay, I'll let him do it this way.
If you bought
Is it fresh Longleaf Garden Burnet Root?
Then crush it and use it
Apply on wound
That's it
Oral and topical treatment
Helps wounds, astringes, stops bleeding,
and promotes tissue regeneration
Longleaf Garden Burnet Rootis a medicine for cooling blood and stopping bleeding
Can reduce swelling, detoxify and heal wounds
Not only can it handle trauma
For hemorrhoidal bleeding
Vomiting blood, blood in the stool, and other bleeding problems
It also helps.
Friends who like this video
Please click on the super thank you button below the video
Give us support